

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

### Md. Faizur Rahman Jewel

Address: 262, Goaltak (Faidabath), P.O-Faidabath Madrasha, P.S-Dakkhinkhan, Uttara, Dhaka-1230.

Mobile:01923-383765/01675-123884

e-mail: <u>iewelldu@gmail.com</u>
Nationality: Bangladeshi
Marital status: Married

Date of Birth: 29 December'1982

### **Career Summary:**

Professional with more than 9 years of experience in Project Management, Coordination, Field Operation, Training, Monitoring & Evaluation, Research, Advocacy in different social cultural settings of Bangladesh. Worked Government Agency and also Worked with International and national development organizations (UCEP Bangladesh & icddr'b). Immense Experience to work with mass people through my whole career. Community based project implementation on Public Health, Entrepreneurship and skills Development, TVET, Conduct training program. I am also Master Trainer of Entrepreneurship. I have experienced in Consultancy on Entrepreneurships and Skills Training and also experience made in Training module. I worked with the major donor project such as USAID, DFID, Oxfam, Save the children, SEIP, Australian Government etc.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# **Present Job Experience**

# **District Training Coordinator**

Entrepreneurship and Skill Development Project (ESDP)

Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA)

# **Prime Minister's Office**

(From 1<sup>st</sup> June' 2019 to 30 June 2021)

Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA) an organization under Prime Minister's Office is an investment promotion and facilitation agency of Bangladesh. BIDA is providing diversified promotion and facilitating services with a view to accelerating industrial development of the country.

The motto of the ESDP (Entrepreneurship and Skills Development Project) is to create new local investors and develop the existing small and medium entrepreneur, showing them paths and ways to make their entrepreneur strong and effective raising investment amount and creating employment opportunities in the 64 districts all over Bangladesh.

As a Training Coordinator coordinates the following activities for district-based District training activities to fulfill the mission and vision of BIDA:

# **Major Responsibility:**

- Design, facilitate and coordination on entrepreneurship development project.
- Selection of trainees (Youth) for the training program.
- Ensure participation of target trainees & monitor quality training implementation.
- Conducted Training Session.
- Assess training standard and summarize pre and post test evaluation report.

- Establish linkage and maintain network and communication with different local and national industries.
- Monitor and supervision of the district office Employees
- Maintain linkage with GO, NGOs and Investor for the development of the program.
- Prepare implementation plan to run project
- Prepare half monthly, monthly and yearly progress report
- Prepare budget and Monitor the program budget and make plan for implementation of budget
- Accountable for bill, voucher and relevant expenses
- Coordinating and preserving year wise auditing
- Established "Entrepreneurs incubator Center"

### Past experience:

1. Deputy Program officer (Monitoring, Evaluation and Research)

**UCEP (Underprivileged Children Educational Program)-Bangladesh** (April 3, 2016 to 30 May'2019) **Major Responsibility:** 

The monitoring activities of UCEP Bangladesh are conducted through monitoring template. This is 'Result Based Monitoring'. I work at MER (monitoring Evaluation Research) Department and conduct the monitoring system. At present, UCEP Bangladesh runs 30 projects, I do the work of monitoring and develop the monitoring system for the programs run by UCEP Bangladesh. Besides my other responsibilities are as follows:

- > To compile monthly monitoring reports from regional offices and projects.
- > To prepare a summary monitoring report based on monthly monitoring report on the regional projects.
- > To prepare list of observations/recommendations based on the visited programs and monitoring reports.
- To make follow-ups queries/visits of the recommendations/observations made. (by MER/management/donor/board) and include the updates in reporting.
- > To coordinate the monitoring functions of regional offices for getting timely reports.
- Programme monitoring and quality assurance of the UCEP Programme
- > To provide input in designing monitoring, evaluation and research planning of projects/programs.
- > To prepare draft quarterly /Six month /annual progress report regarding the running program/project.
- To check quality of data supplied by program teams.
- > To support for carrying out research, assessment and evaluations.
- > To take small research projects for various learning purposes.
- > To organize shared-learning events.
- > To support in capacity building activities around monitoring, evaluation and research.
- > To ensure proper documentation of reports, data of monitoring, evaluation and research.

## **2. Deputy Program officer** (Child and Woman Rights Advocacy)

UCEP (Underprivileged Children Educational Program)-Bangladesh (12 October'14 to 31 March'16) Major Responsibility:

As a head of regional mobilization function, the system has been combined. The following responsibilities of the Head of Regional Mobilization Function are:

- Supervise and build capacity to School based Community mobilizes.
- Monitor progress and report for multiple purposes.
- ➤ To Conduct Counseling and Motivation session to inspire the Students.
- Plan and Coordinate budget built strategic partnership with other organization and institution.
- Plan and manage advocacy and other events.
- Encourage team members to collaborate and work together.
- To prepare Year/ monthly / quietly work plan.
- > To keep coordination among Child and woman Rights and other components in the region.
- To organize cultural and day celebration events and awareness activities at school / community /regional level ensuring the participation of student, family, community and strategic partners.
- > To maintain liaison with local Government and Administration /NGOs/ Educational Institution.
- To organize and conduct capacity building training / workshop and different types of meetings for various stakeholder.
- To conduct survey and Research. (Such as Sexual and Reproductive Health Rights)

# 3. Research Assistant (August 1, 2011 to 31 March 2014)

Centre for Reproductive Health (CRH) icddr, b (International Center for Diarrheal Diseases Research, Bangladesh)
I have Worked as a Research Assistant in icddr,b(International Center for Diarrheal Diseases Research, Bangladesh)
Jointly Working University of California – Davis, USA, Family health International & lamb Hospital.

RDNS (Rang-Din Nutrition Study) a Community Nutrition Clinical trial in Collaboration with University of California – Davis, USA. I have leaded a sub-project taken to determine the iron in tube well water as a part of research on clinical trial. Moreover, I worked in as a team member of 'Quality control Team'. The following duties and responsibilities I conducted under RDNS Clinical Trial study:

- I have worked as a Team Leader (supervisor) of the Tube well water iron measurement Team. I supervised and monitored of the team.
- I have also worked as Quality Control (Process Evaluation and Lab team) Team. Observed and validation the data
- I have gathered experience to write of Research Manual (To measure iron collect of water collected from tube wells) and I have also experience to write Training Manual and Project Proposal Review.
- ➤ I have **gathered experiences** to write Standard Operating Procedure (SOP);(such as **Mother**: Maternal Morbidity and health Expenditure, Health Problems Requiring Hospitalization, Health Care Cost, Knowledge, Attitude, practice, ante natal and post-natal Care, Cost elate to Child birth. **Child**: Child Morbidity and Health Expenditure, General medical Care and Health Care costs).
- I have gained experience on data collection in the area of anthropometry, maternal and child morbidity cost of health care, mother and instant feeding practices.

#### **Education:**

- MSS in Social Welfare (Passing Year: 2009) Institute of Social welfare and Research, University of Dhaka, Result: 2<sup>nd</sup> Class (6<sup>th</sup> position) 58% Marks.
- 2. **Post-Graduation Diploma in Enterprise Development(PGDED)**: Dhaka School of Economics under Dhaka University (Result: 3.28 out of 4) Passing: 2019
- Masters of Public Health (MPH) (Major: Reproductive and Child Health) (Passing Year:2014) Atish Dipankar University of Science and Technology, Result: 3.65 out of 4
- 4. Bachelor of Law (LLB), Bangladesh Law Collage, PassingYear:2018,Result: 2<sup>nd</sup> Class

# **Training:**

S/L	Title of Training	Institution	Major Topic Learned	Duration	Year
1	Training of Trainer (TOT)on	ESDP, BIDA, Prime	Introduction on entrepreneurship &	1 month	2019
	Entrepreneurship & Skill	minister's office	skills development, Develop	7 days	
	Development		Business plan, LC, loan, Supply and		
			linkage, Investment, Ease of doing		
			business, One stop service, Office		
			management.		
2	Youth led Action Research	Campaign for	Community mapping, Action	3 days	2018
		popular	research, mapping of youth issues		
		education.	in Bangladesh, Framework of		
		Coordination with	research, Overview of Action		
		ASPBAE	Research, Process and tools,		
			Advocacy		
3	Monitoring Evaluation for	MDF Training and	M&E, Purpose of M&E, Log frame,	4 days	2017
	Learning	Consultation in	Project cycle, Result based		
		Thailand	monitoring, SDGs, Risk matrix,		
			input, output, output, Outcome, impact, FGD, Most significant		
			change		
4	Monitoring and Evaluation	MDF Training and	M&E, Purpose of M&E, Log frame,	5 days	2016
		Consultation	Project cycle, Result based		

			monitoring, Risk matrix		
	Organizational Development	MDF Training and	Change in organizations, systematic	3 days	2016
	and Management	Consultation	and comprehensive organizational diagnosis, identify different		
5			scenarios to strengthen an		
			organization, develop and priorities		
			strategic options to improve		
			organizational performance.		
6	Basic course on Scientific		Structure of a scientific report	5 days	2016
	writing for mid-level researchers	BRAC University	writing (IMRAD), Ethics, scientific		
	And development		misconduct, literature search and review, make good table and		
	practitioners		figures, TOC, writing qualitative and		
	•		quantitative report		
7	Child Rights	UCEP Bangladesh	Child Right, Mobilization, Result	3 days	2015
			chain, counseling, Advocacy		
8	Gender	Save the Children	Basic Gender learning	2 days	2015
	Quality Control Training for	Rang-Din	Mortality *Blinding *Validity and	12 days	2013
	Quality Control Team	Nutrition Study,	reliability*Biostatistics*Measures of		
9	(Process Evaluation)	icddr'b	central tendency*Research methodology*Research Ethics		
			*Supervision and Monitoring		
10	Research Methodology	Rang-Din	Nutrition and Food security,	12 days	2011
	<i>.</i>	Nutrition Study,	Research Methodology ,Ethics	,	
		icddr'b			
11	RDNS (Rang-Din Nutrition		Foundation Training on Clinical Trail	19 days	2011
	Study) a community nutrition	B B' .	Research Methodology,		
	trial in collaboration with	Rang-Din Nutrition Study,	Circumference, Health facilities Utilization, Food security, New		
	University of California-Davis a jointly research	icddr'b	neonatal and young child		
	a jointly research	icuui b	morbidity/ illness, PNC, ANC, Social-		
			economic and willingness to pay,		
			Communication		

### **Language Proficiency:**

Mother Tongue: Bangla:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking	
Bangla	High	High	High	
English	Good	Good	Good	

#### **ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS ANDCOMPETENCES:**

Office Management, Start new project in District level, Clinical trial (Research), Community based project implementation on Entrepreneurship and skills Development , TVET, rights related; conduct training program; capacity building of staff; conduct quantitative and qualitative research; organizational monitoring, evaluation and research including tools development and techniques; resource mobilisation; strategic partnership building and networking; financial management; proposal writing , concept note writing , SOP and report writing; log-frame and risk matrix writing; advocacy etc.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES:**

Knowledge in MS word, MS excel, Power point, Internet Browsing, office 365.

#### **Research Experience:**

- 1. The thesis of MSS was "The perception and view of the young generation to the aged people" my study period at Dhaka University.
- 2. The thesis of MSS was "Disability" my study period at Dhaka University
- 3. The thesis of MPH was the "The Common Health Problem of child labor worker in some Tobacco Company in Dinajpur District "my study period at Atish Dipankar University of Science and Technology.
- 4. Feasibility Study of Community and Possible Industry's Demand for Mirsarai Economic Zones, Chittagong
- 5. Socio-economic assessment of UCEP Bangladesh working area.

#### **Co-Curricular:**

- Life Member: Social welfare Alumni Association, University of Dhaka
- Life Member: Entrepreneurial Development Club, Dhaka School of Economics, Under DU
- Founder Secretary: Education Development Foundation(edf)
- Ex- Student Association Member of Rajuk Uttara Model College
- Ex Form Leader of Rajuk Uttara Model College
- Award and Certificate in inter college Cricket Tournament of Rajuk Uttara Model College

#### **Teaching Areas:**

- · Entrepreneurship and Skill development
- Research Methodology
- Social Development
- Motivation and Behavioral Science
- Child Abuse and Prevention
- Child Development
- Supply and linkage development

# Writing experience:

- Nischata(To Essay life)
- Uddokta Tari

# Reference:

1. Zaki Hasan	2. Dr. Malay Kanti Mridha
Ex-Country Director	PhD (UC-Davic)
Nutrition International	Professor & Director -NCD, BRACU,JPGSPH
Ex-CEO, UCEP Bangladesh	Ex-Principal Investigator
01730300361	Rang-Din Nutrition Study
zaha3000@gmail.com	icddr'b
	01796583028, malay.mridha@bracu.ac.bd

#### **DECLARATION:**

I am confident that I have the ability to work at a high place on one's own imitative. I will try to my best perform my duties according to the desired Satisfaction of the authority.

I am the Undersigned hereby declare that the above information is true and I will be responsible for any wrong information.

Signature

Md. Faizur Rahman Jewel